#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/salamabiodun (LinkedIn) www.salamabiodun.github.io/ portfolio (Personal)

#### Top Skills

Video Editing Branding & Identity Graphic Design

#### Certifications

Wordpress for web design
Data Analysis with Google Docs
Organic marketing:Facebook Group
for Businesses
Web Development with Wix
Canva For Designers

## Salami Abiodun

Highy creative and multi-talented graphics, web, product and ui/ux designer with extensive experience in media technology and digital marketing.

Lagos State, Nigeria

## Summary

A proven digital strategist with over 5+ years of experience in the support and deployment of solutions at the user, department and corporate level. Highly seasoned and accomplished Professional in development and implementation of business visual designs and branding processes to facilitate day-to-day operations.

Primarily focused on implementation of visual designs. Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities,

Possess a wide range of technical skills. Enjoys being part of a team, as well as managing, motivating and training a productive team, and thrives in high pressure and challenging working environments.

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Proficient at evaluating problems and quickly devising practical solutions.
- Exceptional ability to use latest photo editing software, working with machine and high-end digital cameras.
- Skilled at anticipating, identifying and fulfilling client's needs and clarifying special orders.
- Ability to build relationships with co-workers, supervisors and managers at all levels and an opportunity to receive self-learned skills and life experience from others
- Experienced in advanced on-page and off-page SEO techniques.
- Good knowledge of Social Media and its use in Online Marketing.
- Deep knowledge of search marketing uses of PR, Article, Blogs & RSS Feeds
- Developed corporate brand and designed 17 web sites for internal companies and marketing tools using XML, CSS, HTML, XHTML, JSP, JavaScript, Dreamweaver, Flash, Action-Script and Adobe tools including Go Live, Fireworks, Photoshop, and Illustrator.
- Responsible for site maintenance, editing, and search engine promotion.

- Responsible for creating interactive forms, emails, and presentations for sales and services.
- Created HTML/XHTML/CSS mock-ups for Account Management and Business Development needs.
- Created cutting edge animated flash intros, banners and web based advertising.
- Initiated branding and all graphic design strategies for print and web use.

## Experience

**WORLDLINK BEST TRAVELS & TOURS** 

Social Media Manager January 2023 - Present (4 months)

Lagos State, Nigeria

The Lekki Coliseum
Digital Marketing Specialist
July 2022 - January 2023 (7 months)
Lekki Peninsula, Lagos, Nigeria

Contract

Aladdin Digital Bank
Creative Director
September 2021 - June 2022 (10 months)
Lekki Peninsula, Lagos, Nigeria

#### Contract:

Designs & Illustrations – Promotional Materials for events, such as : Tumblers, Mugs, Pens, Gift Cards, Breath mint packaging, and iPods,

Company Brochures, Specification Sheets, Business Cards and Vinyl Designs for Devices.

- # UI Design for Mobile Software and in-house software
- # 3D Prototype Visualization for Company Products
- # Created and Maintained the Official Website; maintained other Social Media accounts and other online Properties
- # Cleaning up of Marketing stock Photos, Logo design, and Illustrations.

#### Conversation Media Limited

# Communications Specialist 2021 - 2022 (1 year)

Ikeja, Lagos, Nigeria

Contract

#### Teesas

Cinematographer/Video Editor March 2021 - November 2021 (9 months) Nigeria

# 3D Design and Animation, and Video Composition and editing for Marketing Ads

# Creates and edits video composites, and preparing them for rendering in multiple video formats for various purposes (web streaming, presentations, and Hard media)

### BOOK24.ng

Senior Visual Designer February 2020 - January 2021 (1 year)

Nigeria

# Developed a static website with responsive capabilities based off a single mock-up vision in five (5) days.

# Used UI frameworks Bootstrap 3.0, Font Awesome 3.0, Google Analytics.

# Branded and co-directed entire web presence of service based off a single logo

# 3D Design and Animation, and Video Composition and editing for Marketing Ads

# UI Design for Mobile Software and in-house

#### **Topmost Prints**

Photo Editor /Graphic Designer February 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 3 months) Nigeria

Created window graphics, signs, and banners.

# Sold full service business products to local

# Assisted in display of merchandise.

Creates and edits video composites, and preparing them for rendering in multiple video formats for various purposes (web streaming, presentations, and Hard media)

# Designs & Illustrations – Promotional Materials for events, such as: Tumblers, Mugs, Pens, Gift Cards, Breath mint packaging, and iPods,

Company Brochures, Specification Sheets, Business Cards and Vinyl Designs for Devices.

## Education

The Polytechnic, Ibadan
Higher National Diploma, Electronics Option · (2018 - 2021)

The Polytechnic, Ibadan

National Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (June 2015 - September 2017)